<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[The Tao]]></title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[Learning every day.]]></subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://phillipchaffee.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-12-19T21:02:31.353Z</updated>
  <id>http://phillipchaffee.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Phillip Chaffee]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[R probs]]></title>
    <link href="http://phillipchaffee.io/2015/12/20/R-probs/"/>
    <id>http://phillipchaffee.io/2015/12/20/R-probs/</id>
    <published>2015-12-20T01:51:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-12-19T21:02:31.353Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am current taking the class Practical Machine Learning on Coursera offered by John Hopkins University.</p>
<p>The course project is to take sensor data from a study designed to evaluate the correctness in form of dumbbell exercises and build a machine learning algorithm that will predict how well dumbbell lift x was performed.<br>The individual lifts are categorized into five classes: A, B, C, D, E. A is a proper lift. The other four are common mistakes made in dumbbell lifting. The algorithm should predict the class of lift x. </p>
<p>I have processed the training set, and built an algoritm based upon it. The problem arises when I attempt to predict the values of the testing set using <code>predict()</code>. Several of the columns in the testing set<br>contain purely NA values, and cause <code>predict()</code> to throw an error.</p>
<p>I am at a loss because I know that in order to predict correctly the training and test sets should be read in and processed the exact same way. I do not see a way around this. If I process them identically I end up<br>with entire NA columns in the testing set. If I do not the prediction will not work.</p>
<p>It may be time for a break. I will report back later.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I am current taking the class Practical Machine Learning on Coursera offered by John Hopkins University.</p>
<p>The course project is to ]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="R, Coursera, Machine Learning" scheme="http://phillipchaffee.io/tags/R-Coursera-Machine-Learning/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title>
    <link href="http://phillipchaffee.io/2015/12/19/hello-world/"/>
    <id>http://phillipchaffee.io/2015/12/19/hello-world/</id>
    <published>2015-12-19T21:04:29.319Z</published>
    <updated>2015-12-19T21:04:29.319Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello all. I like this streamlined hexo blog written in node.js much better than my previous set up. Just wanted something simple and easy that I could blog on, and here I am!</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Hello all. I like this streamlined hexo blog written in node.js much better than my previous set up. Just wanted something simple and eas]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
